<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Austin Lanari]]></title><description><![CDATA[Coding and comics and comics and coding.]]></description><link>https://austinlanari.com</link><image><url>https://austinlanari.com/logos/logo-512.png</url><title>Austin Lanari</title><link>https://austinlanari.com</link></image><generator>GatsbyJS Material Starter</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 04:58:14 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://austinlanari.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><author><![CDATA[Austin Lanari]]></author><copyright><![CDATA[Copyright © 2017. Austin Lanari]]></copyright><item><title><![CDATA[Work in Progress]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hey hi, I'm Austin Lanari. By day I'm a full stack developer for mobile. What does "full stack" mean in this case, you ask? It means I do…]]></description><link>https://austinlanari.com/work-in-progress</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://austinlanari.com/work-in-progress</guid><category><![CDATA[web design]]></category><category><![CDATA[personal]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Austin Lanari]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hey hi, I&apos;m Austin Lanari. By day I&apos;m a full stack developer for mobile. What does &quot;full stack&quot; mean in this case, you ask?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It means I do... well, I do everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that also means that I get really excited about projects with a lot of breadth and cool things to get done. That&apos;s not so unfortunate for my company (or for my personal and professional development), but when I recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://fuckupsomecomics.com/&quot;&gt;tried to build a comics-blogging platform from scratch&lt;/a&gt;, I got so caught up in building the site that I was never writing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see now, I decided to go with the Ghost blogging platform so that I could focus more on my writing. But in the time before I jumped ship for a pre-built CMS, I spent the better part of 2017 learning what Gatsby had to offer and I remain impressed and in awe of the framework, both in the benefits it offers from a UI perspective and in how it puts developers in a workflow where they learn a lot of cool, core-front-end skills and end up with great results... once things get working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my old personal website was a Jekyll blog that I built while I was still at coding bootcamp, I decided to compromise with myself: as long as I continued my blogging about comics at a clip of one essay per week, I could fool around with Gatsby on my personal website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I never told the more practical part of my brain that I&apos;d make it easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re reading this when I first posted it, you&apos;re on a bare-bones version of Gatsby with all of the boilerplate and... literally no UI tweaks... at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s going to be a long year.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>